And O O
if O O
that O O
was O O
not O O
enough O O
for O O
fame O O
, O O
there O O
was O O
also O O
his O O
prolonged O O
vigour O O
to O O
marvel O O
at O O
. O O
At O O
ninety O O
he O O
was O O
much O O
the O O
same O O
as O O
at O O
fifty O O
. O O
At O O
ninety-nine O O
they O O
began O O
to O O
call O O
him O O
we O O
/ O O
/ O O
- O O
preserved O O
, O O
but O O
unchanged O O
would O O
have O O
been O O
nearer O O
the O O
mark O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
some O O
that O O
shook O O
their O O
heads O O
and O O
thought O O
this O O
was O O
too O O
much O O
of O O
a O O
good O O
thing O O
; O O
it O O
seemed O O
unfair O O
that O O
anyone O O
should O O
possess O O
-LRB- O O
apparently O O
-RRB- O O
perpetual O O
youth O O
as O O
well O O
as O O
-LRB- O O
reputedly O O
-RRB- O O
inexhaustible O O
wealth O O
. O O
` O O
It O O
will O O
have O O
to O O
be O O
paid O O
for O O
, O O
' O O
they O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
It O O
is O O
n't O O
natural O O
, O O
and O O
trouble O O
will O O
come O O
of O O
it O O
! O O
' O O
But O O
so O O
far O O
trouble O O
had O O
not O O
come O O
; O O
and O O
as O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Baggins I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
generous O O
with O O
his O O
money O O
, O O
most O O
people O O
were O O
willing O O
to O O
forgive O O
him O O
his O O
oddities O O
and O O
his O O
good O O
fortune O O
. O O
But O O
he O O
had O O
no O O
close O O
friends O O
, O O
until O O
some O O
of O O
his O O
younger O O
cousins O O
began O O
to O O
grow O O
up O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
and O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
happened O O
to O O
have O O
the O O
same O O
birthday O O
, O O
September O O
22nd O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
had O O
better O O
come O O
and O O
live O O
here O O
, O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
my O O
lad O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
one O O
day O O
; O O
` O O
and O O
then O O
we O O
can O O
celebrate O O
our O O
birthday-parties O O
comfortably O O
together O O
. O O
The O O
history O O
and O O
character O O
of O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
Baggins I-PERSON I-PERSON
became O O
once O O
again O O
the O O
chief O O
topic O O
of O O
conversation O O
; O O
and O O
the O O
older O O
folk O O
suddenly O O
found O O
their O O
reminiscences O O
in O O
welcome O O
demand O O
. O O
Both O O
father O O
and O O
son O O
were O O
on O O
very O O
friendly O O
terms O O
with O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
and O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
But O O
what O O
about O O
this O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
that O O
lives O O
with O O
him O O
? O O
' O O
asked O O
Old I-PERSON I-PERSON
Noakes I-PERSON I-PERSON
of O O
By O O
water O O
. O O
That O O
's O O
a O O
dark O O
bad O O
place O O
, O O
if O O
half O O
the O O
tales O O
be O O
true O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
You O O
're O O
right O O
, O O
Dad O O
! O O
` O O
said O O
the O O
Gaffer O O
. O O
They O O
fool O O
about O O
with O O
boats O O
on O O
that O O
big O O
river O O
- O O
and O O
that O O
is O O
n't O O
natural O O
. O O
Small O O
wonder O O
that O O
trouble O O
came O O
of O O
it O O
, O O
I O O
say O O
. O O
Very O O
much O O
like O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
in O O
more O O
than O O
looks O O
. O O
After O O
all O O
his O O
father O O
was O O
a O O
Baggins I-PERSON O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Drownded O I-PERSON
? O O
' O O
said O O
several O O
voices O O
. O O
They O O
had O O
heard O O
this O O
and O O
other O O
darker O O
rumours O O
before O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
; O O
but O O
hobbits O O
have O O
a O O
passion O O
for O O
family O O
history O O
, O O
and O O
they O O
were O O
ready O O
to O O
hear O O
it O O
again O O
. O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
so O O
they O O
say O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
the O O
Gaffer O O
. O O
She O O
was O O
our O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
's O O
first O O
cousin O O
on O O
the O O
mother O O
's O O
side O O
-LRB- O O
her O O
mother O O
being O O
the O O
youngest O O
of O O
the O I-LOCATION
Old O I-LOCATION
Took O I-LOCATION
's O I-LOCATION
daughters O O
-RRB- O O
; O O
and O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Drogo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
his O O
second O O
cousin O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
And O O
/ O O
heard O O
she O O
pushed O O
him O O
in O O
, O O
and O O
he O O
pulled O O
her O O
in O O
after O O
him O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Sandy O I-PERSON
man O I-PERSON
, O O
the O O
Hobbiton O O
miller O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
should O O
n't O O
listen O O
to O O
all O O
you O O
hear O O
, O O
Sandyman O I-PERSON
, O O
' O O
said O O
the O O
Gaffer O I-PERSON
, O O
who O O
did O O
not O O
much O O
like O O
the O O
miller O O
. O O
` O O
There O O
is O O
n't O O
no O O
call O O
to O O
go O O
talking O O
of O O
pushing O O
and O O
pulling O O
. O O
Boats O O
are O O
quite O O
tricky O O
enough O O
for O O
those O O
that O O
sit O O
still O O
without O O
looking O O
further O O
for O O
the O O
cause O O
of O O
trouble O O
. O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
never O O
did O O
a O O
kinder O O
deed O O
than O O
when O O
he O O
brought O O
the O O
lad O O
back O O
to O O
live O O
among O O
decent O O
folk O O
. O O
` O O
But O O
I O O
reckon O O
it O O
was O O
a O O
nasty O O
shock O O
for O O
those O O
Sackville-Bagginses O I-PERSON
. O O
They O O
thought O O
they O O
were O O
going O O
to O O
get O O
Bag O O
End O O
, O O
that O O
time O O
when O O
he O O
went O O
off O O
and O O
was O O
thought O O
to O O
be O O
dead O O
. O O
And O O
then O O
he O O
comes O O
back O O
and O O
orders O O
them O O
off O O
; O O
and O O
he O O
goes O O
on O O
living O O
and O O
living O O
, O O
and O O
never O O
looking O O
a O O
day O O
older O O
, O O
bless O O
him O O
! O O
And O O
suddenly O O
he O O
produces O O
an O O
heir O O
, O O
and O O
has O O
all O O
the O O
papers O O
made O O
out O O
proper O O
. O O
The O O
Sackville-Bagginses O I-LOCATION
wo O O
n't O O
never O O
see O O
the O O
inside O O
of O O
Bag O O
End O O
now O O
, O O
or O O
it O O
is O O
to O O
be O O
hoped O O
not O O
. O O
` O O
All O O
the O O
top O O
of O O
your O O
hill O O
is O O
full O O
of O O
tunnels O O
packed O O
with O O
chests O O
of O O
gold O O
and O O
silver O O
, O O
and O O
jools O O
, O O
by O O
what O O
I O O
've O O
heard O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Then O O
you O O
've O O
heard O O
more O O
than O O
I O O
can O O
speak O O
to O O
, O O
' O O
answered O O
the O O
Gaffer O O
. O O
I O O
know O O
nothing O O
about O O
jools O O
. O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
is O O
free O O
with O O
his O O
money O O
, O O
and O O
there O O
seems O O
no O O
lack O O
of O O
it O O
; O O
but O O
I O O
know O O
of O O
no O O
tunnel-making O O
. O O
I O O
saw O O
Mr. O O
Bilbo O I-PERSON
when O O
he O O
came O O
back O O
, O O
a O O
matter O O
of O O
sixty O O
years O O
ago O O
, O O
when O O
I O O
was O O
a O O
lad O O
. O O
And O O
in O O
the O O
middle O O
of O O
it O O
all O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
comes O O
up O O
the O O
Hill O I-ORGANIZATION
with O O
a O O
pony O O
and O O
some O O
mighty O O
big O O
bags O O
and O O
a O O
couple O O
of O O
chests O O
. O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
doubt O O
they O O
were O O
mostly O O
full O O
of O O
treasure O O
he O O
had O O
picked O O
up O O
in O O
foreign O O
parts O O
, O O
where O O
there O O
be O O
mountains O O
of O O
gold O O
, O O
they O O
say O O
; O O
but O O
there O O
was O O
n't O O
enough O O
to O O
fill O O
tunnels O O
. O O
But O O
my O O
lad O O
Sam O I-PERSON
will O O
know O O
more O O
about O O
that O O
. O O
He O O
's O O
in O O
and O O
out O O
of O O
Bag O I-ORGANIZATION
End O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
Crazy O O
about O O
stories O O
of O O
the O O
old O O
days O O
he O O
is O O
, O O
and O O
he O O
listens O O
to O O
all O O
Mr. O O
Bilbo O I-PERSON
's O O
tales O O
. O O
Mr. I-PERSON O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
has O O
learned O O
him O O
his O O
letters O O
- O O
meaning O O
no O O
harm O O
, O O
mark O O
you O O
, O O
and O O
I O O
hope O O
no O O
harm O O
will O O
come O O
of O O
it O O
. O O
` O O
Elves O O
and O O
Dragons O O
' O O
Isays O O
to O O
him O O
. O O
` O O
Cabbages O O
and O O
potatoes O O
are O O
better O O
for O O
me O O
and O O
you O O
. O O
Do O O
n't O O
go O O
getting O O
mixed O O
up O O
in O O
the O O
business O O
of O O
your O O
betters O O
, O O
or O O
you O O
'll O O
land O O
in O O
trouble O O
too O O
big O O
for O O
you O O
, O O
' O O
I O O
says O O
to O O
him O O
. O O
And O O
I O O
might O O
say O O
it O O
to O O
others O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
added O O
with O O
a O O
look O O
at O O
the O O
stranger O O
and O O
the O O
miller O O
. O O
But O O
the O O
Gaffer O O
did O O
not O O
convince O O
his O O
audience O O
. O O
The O O
legend O O
of O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
's O O
wealth O O
was O O
now O O
too O O
firmly O O
fixed O O
in O O
the O O
minds O O
of O O
the O O
younger O O
generation O O
of O O
hobbits O O
. O O
` O O
Ah O O
, O O
but O O
he O O
has O O
likely O O
enough O O
been O O
adding O O
to O O
what O O
he O O
brought O O
at O O
first O O
, O O
' O O
argued O O
the O O
miller O O
, O O
voicing O O
common O O
opinion O O
. O O
` O O
He O O
's O O
often O O
away O O
from O O
home O O
. O O
You O O
can O O
say O O
what O O
you O O
like O O
, O O
Gaffer O O
, O O
but O O
Bag O O
End O O
's O O
a O O
queer O O
place O O
, O O
and O O
its O O
folk O O
are O O
queerer O O
. O O
If O O
that O O
's O O
being O O
queer O O
, O O
then O O
we O O
could O O
do O O
with O O
a O O
bit O O
more O O
queerness O O
in O O
these O O
parts O O
. O O
There O O
's O O
some O O
not O O
far O O
away O O
that O O
would O O
n't O O
offer O O
a O O
pint O O
of O O
beer O O
to O O
a O O
friend O O
, O O
if O O
they O O
lived O O
in O O
a O O
hole O O
with O O
golden O O
walls O O
. O O
But O O
they O O
do O O
things O O
proper O O
at O O
Bag O O
End O O
. O O
Our O O
Sam I-PERSON I-PERSON
says O O
that O O
everyone O O
's O O
going O O
to O O
be O O
invited O O
to O O
the O O
party O O
, O O
and O O
there O O
's O O
going O O
to O O
be O O
presents O O
, O O
mark O O
you O O
, O O
presents O O
for O O
all O O
- O O
this O O
very O O
month O O
as O O
is O O
. O O
' O O
That O O
very O O
month O O
was O O
September O O
, O O
and O O
as O O
fine O O
as O O
you O O
could O O
ask O O
. O O
A O O
day O O
or O O
two O O
later O O
a O O
rumour O O
-LRB- O O
probably O O
started O O
by O O
the O O
knowledgeable O O
Sam I-PERSON I-PERSON
-RRB- O I-PERSON
was O O
spread O O
about O O
that O O
there O O
were O O
going O O
to O O
be O O
fireworks O O
- O O
fireworks O O
, O O
what O O
is O O
more O O
, O O
such O O
as O O
had O O
not O O
been O O
seen O O
in O O
the O O
Shire O I-ORGANIZATION
for O O
nigh O O
on O O
a O O
century O O
, O O
not O O
indeed O O
since O O
the O O
Old O O
Took O O
died O O
. O O
Days O O
passed O O
and O O
The O O
Day O O
drew O O
nearer O O
. O O
An O O
odd-looking O O
waggon O O
laden O O
with O O
odd-looking O O
packages O O
rolled O O
into O O
Hobbiton O I-LOCATION
one O O
evening O O
and O O
toiled O O
up O O
the O O
Hill O O
to O O
Bag O O
End O O
. O O
The O O
startled O O
hobbits O O
peered O O
out O O
of O O
lamplit O O
doors O O
to O O
gape O O
at O O
it O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
driven O O
by O O
outlandish O O
folk O O
, O O
singing O O
strange O O
songs O O
: O O
dwarves O O
with O O
long O O
beards O O
and O O
deep O O
hoods O O
. O O
A O O
few O O
of O O
them O O
remained O O
at O O
Bag O O
End O O
. O O
An O O
old O O
man O O
was O O
driving O O
it O O
all O O
alone O O
. O O
He O O
wore O O
a O O
tall O O
pointed O O
blue O O
hat O O
, O O
a O O
long O O
grey O O
cloak O O
, O O
and O O
a O O
silver O O
scarf O O
. O O
He O O
had O O
a O O
long O O
white O O
beard O O
and O O
bushy O O
eyebrows O O
that O O
stuck O O
out O O
beyond O O
the O O
brim O O
of O O
his O O
hat O O
. O O
Small O O
hobbit-children O O
ran O O
after O O
the O O
cart O O
all O O
through O O
Hobbiton O O
and O O
right O O
up O O
the O O
hill O O
. O O
It O O
had O O
a O O
cargo O O
of O O
fireworks O O
, O O
as O O
they O O
rightly O O
guessed O O
. O O
His O O
real O O
business O O
was O O
far O O
more O O
difficult O O
and O O
dangerous O O
, O O
but O O
the O O
Shire-folk O I-LOCATION
knew O O
nothing O O
about O O
it O O
. O O
To O O
them O O
he O O
was O O
just O O
one O O
of O O
the O O
` O O
attractions O O
' O O
at O O
the O O
Party O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
' O O
G O O
for O O
Grand O O
! O O
` O O
they O O
shouted O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
old O O
man O O
smiled O O
. O O
They O O
knew O O
him O O
by O O
sight O O
, O O
though O O
he O O
only O O
appeared O O
in O O
Hobbiton O I-LOCATION
occasionally O O
and O O
never O O
stopped O O
long O O
; O O
but O O
neither O O
they O O
nor O O
any O O
but O O
the O O
oldest O O
of O O
their O O
elders O O
had O O
seen O O
one O O
of O O
his O O
firework O O
displays O O
- O O
they O O
now O O
belonged O O
to O O
the O O
legendary O O
past O O
. O O
When O O
the O O
old O O
man O O
, O O
helped O O
by O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
and O O
some O O
dwarves O O
, O O
had O O
finished O O
unloading O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
gave O O
a O O
few O O
pennies O O
away O O
; O O
but O O
not O O
a O O
single O O
squib O O
or O O
cracker O O
was O O
forthcoming O O
, O O
to O O
the O O
disappointment O O
of O O
the O O
onlookers O O
. O O
` O O
Run O O
away O O
now O O
! O O
` O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
You O O
will O O
get O O
plenty O O
when O O
the O O
time O O
comes O O
. O O
' O O
Then O O
he O O
disappeared O O
inside O O
with O O
Bilbo O I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
the O O
door O O
was O O
shut O O
. O O
The O O
young O O
hobbits O O
stared O O
at O O
the O O
door O O
in O O
vain O O
for O O
a O O
while O O
, O O
and O O
then O O
made O O
off O O
, O O
feeling O O
that O O
the O O
day O O
of O O
the O O
party O O
would O O
never O O
come O O
. O O
Inside O O
Bag O O
End O O
, O O
Bilbo I-PERSON O
and O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
were O O
sitting O O
at O O
the O O
open O O
window O O
of O O
a O O
small O O
room O O
looking O O
out O O
west O O
on O O
to O O
the O O
garden O O
. O O
The O O
late O O
afternoon O O
was O O
bright O O
and O O
peaceful O O
. O O
The O O
flowers O O
glowed O O
red O O
and O O
golden O O
: O O
snap-dragons O O
and O O
sun-flowers O O
, O O
and O O
nasturtiums O O
trailing O O
all O O
over O O
the O O
turf O O
walls O O
and O O
peeping O O
in O O
at O O
the O O
round O O
windows O O
. O O
` O O
How O O
bright O O
your O O
garden O O
looks O O
! O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
I O O
am O O
very O O
fond O O
indeed O O
of O O
it O O
, O O
and O O
of O O
all O O
the O O
dear O O
old O O
Shire O I-ORGANIZATION
; O O
but O O
I O O
think O O
I O O
need O O
a O O
holiday O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
You O O
mean O O
to O O
go O O
on O O
with O O
your O O
plan O O
then O O
? O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
do O O
. O O
I O O
made O O
up O O
my O O
mind O O
months O O
ago O O
, O O
and O O
I O O
have O O
n't O O
changed O O
it O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Very O O
well O O
. O O
It O O
is O O
no O O
good O O
saying O O
any O O
more O O
. O O
Stick O O
to O O
your O O
plan O O
- O O
your O O
whole O O
plan O O
, O O
mind O O
- O O
and O O
I O O
hope O O
it O O
will O O
turn O O
out O O
for O O
the O O
best O O
, O O
for O O
you O O
, O O
and O O
for O O
all O O
of O O
us O O
. O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
hope O O
so O O
. O O
Anyway O O
I O O
mean O O
to O O
enjoy O O
myself O O
on O O
Thursday O O
, O O
and O O
have O O
my O O
little O O
joke O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Who O O
will O O
laugh O O
, O O
I O O
wonder O O
? O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
shaking O O
his O O
head O O
. O O
` O O
We O O
shall O O
see O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
The O O
next O O
day O O
more O O
carts O O
rolled O O
up O O
the O O
Hill O I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
and O O
still O O
more O O
carts O O
. O O
There O O
might O O
have O O
been O O
some O O
grumbling O O
about O O
` O O
dealing O O
locally O O
' O O
, O O
but O O
that O O
very O O
week O O
orders O O
began O O
to O O
pour O O
out O O
of O O
Bag O I-ORGANIZATION
End O I-ORGANIZATION
for O O
every O O
kind O O
of O O
provision O O
, O O
commodity O O
, O O
or O O
luxury O O
that O O
could O O
be O O
obtained O O
in O O
Hobbiton O I-LOCATION
or O O
Bywater O O
or O O
anywhere O O
in O O
the O O
neighbourhood O O
. O O
People O O
became O O
enthusiastic O O
; O O
and O O
they O O
began O O
to O O
tick O O
off O O
the O O
days O O
on O O
the O O
calendar O O
; O O
and O O
they O O
watched O O
eagerly O O
for O O
the O O
postman O O
, O O
hoping O O
for O O
invitations O O
. O O
Before O O
long O O
the O O
invitations O O
began O O
pouring O O
out O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
Hobbiton O O
post-office O O
was O O
blocked O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
Bywater O O
post-office O O
was O O
snowed O O
under O O
, O O
and O O
voluntary O O
assistant O O
postmen O O
were O O
called O O
for O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
a O O
constant O O
stream O O
of O O
them O O
going O O
up O O
the O O
Hill O I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
carrying O O
hundreds O O
of O O
polite O O
variations O O
on O O
Thank O O
you O O
, O O
I O O
shall O O
certainly O O
come O O
. O O
A O O
notice O O
appeared O O
on O O
the O O
gate O O
at O O
Bag O O
End O O
: O O
NO O O
ADMITTANCE O O
EXCEPT O O
ON O I-ORGANIZATION
PARTY O I-ORGANIZATION
BUSINESS O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
Even O O
those O O
who O O
had O O
, O O
or O O
pretended O O
to O O
have O O
Party O I-ORGANIZATION
Business O I-ORGANIZATION
were O O
seldom O O
allowed O O
inside O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
busy O O
: O O
writing O O
invitations O O
, O O
ticking O O
off O O
answers O O
, O O
packing O O
up O O
presents O O
, O O
and O O
making O O
some O O
private O O
preparations O O
of O O
his O O
own O O
. O O
From O O
the O O
time O O
of O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
s O O
arrival O O
he O O
remained O O
hidden O O
from O O
view O O
. O O
A O O
special O O
entrance O O
was O O
cut O O
into O O
the O O
bank O O
leading O O
to O O
the O O
road O O
, O O
and O O
wide O O
steps O O
and O O
a O O
large O O
white O O
gate O O
were O O
built O O
there O O
. O O
The O O
three O O
hobbit-families O O
of O O
Bagshot O I-ORGANIZATION
Row O I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
adjoining O O
the O O
field O O
, O O
were O O
intensely O O
interested O O
and O O
generally O O
envied O O
. O O
The O O
tents O O
began O O
to O O
go O O
up O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
a O O
specially O O
large O O
pavilion O O
, O O
so O O
big O O
that O O
the O O
tree O O
that O O
grew O O
in O O
the O O
field O O
was O O
right O O
inside O O
it O O
, O O
and O O
stood O O
proudly O O
near O O
one O O
end O O
, O O
at O O
the O O
head O O
of O O
the O O
chief O O
table O O
. O O
Lanterns O O
were O O
hung O O
on O O
all O O
its O O
branches O O
. O O
More O O
promising O O
still O O
-LRB- O O
to O O
the O O
hobbits O O
' O O
mind O O
-RRB- O O
: O O
an O O
enormous O O
open-air O O
kitchen O O
was O O
erected O O
in O O
the O O
north O O
corner O O
of O O
the O O
field O O
. O O
A O O
draught O O
of O O
cooks O O
, O O
from O O
every O O
inn O O
and O O
eating-house O O
for O O
miles O O
around O O
, O O
arrived O O
to O O
supplement O O
the O O
dwarves O O
and O O
other O O
odd O O
folk O O
that O O
were O O
quartered O O
at O O
Bag O O
End O O
. O O
Excitement O O
rose O O
to O O
its O O
height O O
. O O
Then O O
the O O
weather O O
clouded O O
over O O
. O O
That O O
was O O
on O O
Wednesday O O
the O O
eve O O
of O O
the O O
Party O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
Anxiety O O
was O O
intense O O
. O O
Then O O
Thursday O O
, O O
September O O
the O O
22nd O O
, O O
actually O O
dawned O O
. O O
The O O
sun O O
got O O
up O O
, O O
the O O
clouds O O
vanished O O
, O O
flags O O
were O O
unfurled O O
and O O
the O O
fun O O
began O O
. O O
Practically O O
everybody O O
living O O
near O O
was O O
invited O O
. O O
Many O O
people O O
from O O
other O O
parts O O
of O O
the O O
Shire O I-ORGANIZATION
were O O
also O O
asked O O
; O O
and O O
there O O
were O O
even O O
a O O
few O O
from O O
outside O O
the O O
borders O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
met O O
the O O
guests O O
-LRB- O O
and O O
additions O O
-RRB- O O
at O O
the O O
new O O
white O O
gate O O
in O O
person O O
. O O
Hobbits O O
give O O
presents O O
to O O
other O O
people O O
on O O
their O O
own O O
birthdays O O
. O O
Not O O
very O O
expensive O O
ones O O
, O O
as O O
a O O
rule O O
, O O
and O O
not O O
so O O
lavishly O O
as O O
on O O
this O O
occasion O O
; O O
but O O
it O O
was O O
not O O
a O O
bad O O
system O O
. O O
Actually O O
in O O
Hobbiton O I-LOCATION
and O O
Bywater O I-LOCATION
every O O
day O O
in O O
the O O
year O O
it O O
was O O
somebody O O
's O O
birthday O O
, O O
so O O
that O O
every O O
hobbit O O
in O O
those O O
parts O O
had O O
a O O
fair O O
chance O O
of O O
at O O
least O O
one O O
present O O
at O O
least O O
once O O
a O O
week O O
. O O
But O O
they O O
never O O
got O O
tired O O
of O O
them O O
. O O
On O O
this O O
occasion O O
the O O
presents O O
were O O
unusually O O
good O O
. O O
The O O
hobbit-children O O
were O O
so O O
excited O O
that O O
for O O
a O O
while O O
they O O
almost O O
forgot O O
about O O
eating O O
. O O
When O O
every O O
guest O O
had O O
been O O
welcomed O O
and O O
was O O
finally O O
inside O O
the O O
gate O O
, O O
there O O
were O O
songs O O
, O O
dances O O
, O O
music O O
, O O
games O O
, O O
and O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
food O O
and O O
drink O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
three O O
official O O
meals O O
: O O
lunch O O
, O O
tea O O
, O O
and O O
dinner O O
-LRB- O O
or O O
supper O O
-RRB- O O
. O O
But O O
lunch O O
and O O
tea O O
were O O
marked O O
chiefly O O
by O O
the O O
fact O O
that O O
at O O
those O O
times O O
all O O
the O O
guests O O
were O O
sitting O O
down O O
and O O
eating O O
together O O
. O O
At O O
other O O
times O O
there O O
were O O
merely O O
lots O O
of O O
people O O
eating O O
and O O
drinking O O
- O O
continuously O O
from O O
elevenses O O
until O O
six-thirty O O
, O O
when O O
the O O
fireworks O O
started O O
. O O
The O O
fireworks O O
were O O
by O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
: O O
they O O
were O O
not O O
only O O
brought O O
by O O
him O O
, O O
but O O
designed O O
and O O
made O O
by O O
him O O
; O O
and O O
the O O
special O O
effects O O
, O O
set O O
pieces O O
, O O
and O O
flights O O
of O O
rockets O O
were O O
let O O
off O O
by O O
him O O
. O O
But O O
there O O
was O O
also O O
a O O
generous O O
distribution O O
of O O
squibs O O
, O O
crackers O O
, O O
backarappers O O
, O O
sparklers O O
, O O
torches O O
, O O
dwarf-candles O O
, O O
elf-fountains O O
, O O
goblin-barkers O O
and O O
thunder-claps O O
. O O
They O O
were O O
all O O
superb O O
. O O
The O O
art O O
of O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
improved O O
with O O
age O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
rockets O O
like O O
a O O
flight O O
of O O
scintillating O O
birds O O
singing O O
with O O
sweet O O
voices O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
green O O
trees O O
with O O
trunks O O
of O O
dark O O
smoke O O
: O O
their O O
leaves O O
opened O O
like O O
a O O
whole O O
spring O O
unfolding O O
in O O
a O O
moment O O
, O O
and O O
their O O
shining O O
branches O O
dropped O O
glowing O O
flowers O O
down O O
upon O O
the O O
astonished O O
hobbits O O
, O O
disappearing O O
with O O
a O O
sweet O O
scent O O
just O O
before O O
they O O
touched O O
their O O
upturned O O
faces O O
. O O
And O O
there O O
was O O
also O O
one O O
last O O
surprise O O
, O O
in O O
honour O O
of O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
it O O
startled O O
the O O
hobbits O O
exceedingly O O
, O O
as O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
intended O O
. O O
The O O
lights O O
went O O
out O O
. O O
A O O
great O O
smoke O O
went O O
up O O
. O O
It O O
shaped O O
itself O O
like O O
a O O
mountain O O
seen O O
in O O
the O O
distance O O
, O O
and O O
began O O
to O O
glow O O
at O O
the O O
summit O O
. O O
It O O
spouted O O
green O O
and O O
scarlet O O
flames O O
. O O
Out O O
flew O O
a O O
red-golden O O
dragon O O
- O O
not O O
life-size O O
, O O
but O O
terribly O O
life-like O O
: O O
fire O O
came O O
from O O
his O O
jaws O O
, O O
his O O
eyes O O
glared O O
down O O
; O O
there O O
was O O
a O O
roar O O
, O O
and O O
he O O
whizzed O O
three O O
times O O
over O O
the O O
heads O O
of O O
the O O
crowd O O
. O O
They O O
all O O
ducked O O
, O O
and O O
many O O
fell O O
flat O O
on O O
their O O
faces O O
. O O
The O O
dragon O O
passed O O
like O O
an O O
express O O
train O O
, O O
turned O O
a O O
somersault O O
, O O
and O O
burst O O
over O O
Bywater O I-LOCATION
with O O
a O O
deafening O O
explosion O O
. O O
That O O
is O O
the O O
signal O O
for O O
supper O O
! O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
The O O
pain O O
and O O
alarm O O
vanished O O
at O O
once O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
prostrate O O
hobbits O O
leaped O O
to O O
their O O
feet O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
a O O
splendid O O
supper O O
for O O
everyone O O
; O O
for O O
everyone O O
, O O
that O O
is O O
, O O
except O O
those O O
invited O O
to O O
the O O
special O O
family O O
dinner-party O O
. O O
This O O
was O O
held O O
in O O
the O O
great O O
pavilion O O
with O O
the O O
tree O O
. O O
The O O
invitations O O
were O O
limited O O
to O O
twelve O O
dozen O O
-LRB- O O
a O O
number O O
also O O
called O O
by O O
the O O
hobbits O O
one O O
Gross O O
, O O
though O O
the O O
word O O
was O O
not O O
considered O O
proper O O
to O O
use O O
of O O
people O O
-RRB- O O
; O O
and O O
the O O
guests O O
were O O
selected O O
from O O
all O O
the O O
families O O
to O O
which O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
and O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
were O O
related O O
, O O
with O O
the O O
addition O O
of O O
a O O
few O O
special O O
unrelated O O
friends O O
-LRB- O O
such O O
as O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
-RRB- O O
. O O
Many O O
young O O
hobbits O O
were O O
included O O
, O O
and O O
present O O
by O O
parental O O
permission O O
; O O
for O O
hobbits O O
were O O
easy-going O O
with O O
their O O
children O O
in O O
the O O
matter O O
of O O
sitting O O
up O O
late O O
, O O
especially O O
when O O
there O O
was O O
a O O
chance O O
of O O
getting O O
them O O
a O O
free O O
meal O O
. O O
Bringing O O
up O O
young O O
hobbits O O
took O O
a O O
lot O O
of O O
provender O O
. O O
Some O O
of O O
these O O
were O O
only O O
very O O
distantly O O
connected O O
with O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
some O O
of O O
them O O
had O O
hardly O O
ever O O
been O O
in O O
Hobbiton O I-LOCATION
before O O
, O O
as O O
they O O
lived O O
in O O
remote O O
corners O O
of O O
the O O
Shire O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
The O O
Sackville-Bagginses O O
were O O
not O O
forgotten O O
. O O
They O O
disliked O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
and O O
detested O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
but O O
so O O
magnificent O O
was O O
the O O
invitation O O
card O O
, O O
written O O
in O O
golden O O
ink O O
, O O
that O O
they O O
had O O
felt O O
it O O
was O O
impossible O O
to O O
refuse O O
. O O
Besides O O
, O O
their O O
cousin O O
, O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
had O O
been O O
specializing O O
in O O
food O O
for O O
many O O
years O O
and O O
his O O
table O O
had O O
a O O
high O O
reputation O O
. O O
All O O
the O O
one O O
hundred O O
and O O
forty-four O O
guests O O
expected O O
a O O
pleasant O O
feast O O
; O O
though O O
they O O
rather O O
dreaded O O
the O O
after-dinner O O
speech O O
of O O
their O O
host O O
-LRB- O O
an O O
inevitable O O
item O O
-RRB- O O
. O O
The O O
guests O O
were O O
not O O
disappointed O O
: O O
they O O
had O O
a O O
very O O
pleasant O O
feast O O
, O O
in O O
fact O O
an O O
engrossing O O
entertainment O O
: O O
rich O O
, O O
abundant O O
, O O
varied O O
, O O
and O O
prolonged O O
. O O
The O O
purchase O O
of O O
provisions O O
fell O O
almost O O
to O O
nothing O O
throughout O O
the O O
district O O
in O O
the O O
ensuing O O
weeks O O
; O O
but O O
as O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
's O O
catering O O
had O O
depleted O O
the O O
stocks O O
of O O
most O O
stores O O
, O O
cellars O O
and O O
warehouses O O
for O O
miles O O
around O O
, O O
that O O
did O O
not O O
matter O O
much O O
. O O
After O O
the O O
feast O O
-LRB- O O
more O O
or O O
less O O
-RRB- O O
came O O
the O O
Speech O O
. O O
Most O O
of O O
the O O
company O O
were O O
, O O
however O O
, O O
now O O
in O O
a O O
tolerant O O
mood O O
, O O
at O O
that O O
delightful O O
stage O O
which O O
they O O
called O O
' O O
filling O O
up O O
the O O
corners O O
' O O
. O O
They O O
were O O
sipping O O
their O O
favourite O O
drinks O O
, O O
and O O
nibbling O O
at O O
their O O
favourite O O
dainties O O
, O O
and O O
their O O
fears O O
were O O
forgotten O O
. O O
They O O
were O O
prepared O O
to O O
listen O O
to O O
anything O O
, O O
and O O
to O O
cheer O O
at O O
every O O
full O O
stop O O
. O O
My O O
dear O O
People O O
, O O
began O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
rising O O
in O O
his O O
place O O
. O O
' O O
Flear O O
! O O
Flear O O
! O O
Hear O O
! O O
' O O
they O O
shouted O O
, O O
and O O
kept O O
on O O
repeating O O
it O O
in O O
chorus O O
, O O
seeming O O
reluctant O O
to O O
follow O O
their O O
own O O
advice O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
left O O
his O O
place O O
and O O
went O O
and O O
stood O O
on O O
a O O
chair O O
under O O
the O O
illuminated O O
tree O O
. O O
The O O
light O O
of O O
the O O
lanterns O O
fell O O
on O O
his O O
beaming O O
face O O
; O O
the O O
golden O O
buttons O O
shone O O
on O O
his O O
embroidered O O
silk O O
waistcoat O O
. O O
They O O
could O O
all O O
see O O
him O O
standing O O
, O O
waving O O
one O O
hand O O
in O O
the O O
air O O
, O O
the O O
other O O
was O O
in O O
his O O
trouser-pocket O O
. O O
` O O
ProudFEET O O
! O O
' O O
shouted O O
an O O
elderly O O
hobbit O O
from O O
the O O
back O O
of O O
the O O
pavilion O O
. O O
Proudfoots O I-LOCATION
, O O
repeated O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
Also O O
my O O
good O O
Sackville-Bagginses O I-PERSON
that O O
I O O
welcome O O
back O O
at O O
last O O
to O O
Bag O O
End O O
. O O
Today O O
is O O
my O O
one O O
hundred O O
and O O
eleventh O O
birthday O O
: O O
I O O
am O O
eleventy-one O O
today O O
! O O
' O O
Hurray O O
! O O
Hurray O O
! O O
Many O O
Happy O O
Returns O O
! O O
' O O
they O O
shouted O O
, O O
and O O
they O O
hammered O O
joyously O O
on O O
the O O
tables O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
doing O O
splendidly O O
. O O
This O O
was O O
the O O
sort O O
of O O
stuff O O
they O O
liked O O
: O O
short O O
and O O
obvious O O
. O O
I O O
hope O O
you O O
are O O
all O O
enjoying O O
yourselves O O
as O O
much O O
as O O
I O O
am O O
. O O
Deafening O O
cheers O O
. O O
Cries O O
of O O
Yes O O
-LRB- O O
and O O
No O O
-RRB- O O
. O O
Noises O O
of O O
trumpets O O
and O O
horns O O
, O O
pipes O O
and O O
flutes O O
, O O
and O O
other O O
musical O O
instruments O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
, O O
as O O
has O O
been O O
said O O
, O O
many O O
young O O
hobbits O O
present O O
. O O
Hundreds O O
of O O
musical O O
crackers O O
had O O
been O O
pulled O O
. O O
They O O
contained O O
instruments O O
, O O
small O O
, O O
but O O
of O O
perfect O O
make O O
and O O
enchanting O O
tones O O
. O O
But O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
had O O
not O O
finished O O
. O O
Seizing O O
a O O
horn O O
from O O
a O O
youngster O O
near O O
by O O
, O O
he O O
blew O O
three O O
loud O O
hoots O O
. O O
The O O
noise O O
subsided O O
. O O
/ O O
shall O O
not O O
keep O O
you O O
long O O
, O O
he O O
cried O O
. O O
Cheers O O
from O O
all O O
the O O
assembly O O
. O O
/ O O
have O O
called O O
you O O
all O O
together O O
for O O
a O O
Purpose O O
. O O
Something O O
in O O
the O O
way O O
that O O
he O O
said O O
this O O
made O O
an O O
impression O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
almost O O
silence O O
, O O
and O O
one O O
or O O
two O O
of O O
the O O
Tooks O O
pricked O O
up O O
their O O
ears O O
. O O
Indeed O O
, O O
for O O
Three O O
Purposes O O
! O O
First O O
of O O
all O O
, O O
to O O
tell O O
you O O
that O O
I O O
am O O
immensely O O
fond O O
of O O
you O O
all O O
, O O
and O O
that O O
eleventy-one O O
years O O
is O O
too O O
short O O
a O O
time O O
to O O
live O O
among O O
such O O
excellent O O
and O O
admirable O O
hobbits O O
. O O
Tremendous O O
outburst O O
of O O
approval O O
. O O
/ O O
do O O
n't O O
know O O
half O O
of O O
you O O
half O O
as O O
well O O
as O O
I O O
should O O
like O O
; O O
and O O
I O O
like O O
less O O
than O O
half O O
of O O
you O O
half O O
as O O
well O O
as O O
you O O
deserve O O
. O O
This O O
was O O
unexpected O O
and O O
rather O O
difficult O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
some O O
scattered O O
clapping O O
, O O
but O O
most O O
of O O
them O O
were O O
trying O O
to O O
work O O
it O O
out O O
and O O
see O O
if O O
it O O
came O O
to O O
a O O
compliment O O
. O O
Secondly O O
, O O
to O O
celebrate O O
my O O
birthday O O
. O O
Cheers O O
again O O
. O O
I O O
should O O
say O O
: O O
OUR O O
birthday O O
. O O
He O O
comes O O
of O O
age O O
and O O
into O O
his O O
inheritance O O
today O O
. O O
Some O O
perfunctory O O
clapping O O
by O O
the O O
elders O O
; O O
and O O
some O O
loud O O
shouts O O
of O O
' O O
Frodo I-PERSON O
! O O
Frodo I-PERSON O
! O O
Jolly O I-PERSON
old O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
' O O
from O O
the O O
juniors O O
. O O
The O O
Sackville-Bagginses I-PERSON O
scowled O O
, O O
and O O
wondered O O
what O O
was O O
meant O O
by O O
` O O
coming O O
into O O
his O O
inheritance O O
' O O
. O O
Together O O
we O O
score O O
one O O
hundred O O
and O O
forty-four O O
. O O
Your O O
numbers O O
were O O
chosen O O
to O O
fit O O
this O O
remarkable O O
total O O
: O O
One O O
Gross O O
, O O
if O O
I O O
may O O
use O O
the O O
expression O O
. O O
No O O
cheers O O
. O O
This O O
was O O
ridiculous O O
. O O
Many O O
of O O
his O O
guests O O
, O O
and O O
especially O O
the O O
Sackville-Bagginses O O
, O O
were O O
insulted O O
, O O
feeling O O
sure O O
they O O
had O O
only O O
been O O
asked O O
to O O
fill O O
up O O
the O O
required O O
number O O
, O O
like O O
goods O O
in O O
a O O
package O O
. O O
` O O
One O O
Gross O O
, O O
indeed O O
! O O
Vulgar O O
expression O O
. O O
I O O
was O O
only O O
fifty-one O O
then O O
, O O
and O O
birthdays O O
did O O
not O O
seem O O
so O O
important O O
. O O
The O O
banquet O O
was O O
very O O
splendid O O
, O O
however O O
, O O
though O O
I O O
had O O
a O O
bad O O
cold O O
at O O
the O O
time O O
, O O
I O O
remember O O
, O O
and O O
could O O
only O O
say O O
` O O
thagyou O O
very O O
buch O O
' O O
. O O
I O O
now O O
repeat O O
it O O
more O O
correctly O O
: O O
Thank O O
you O O
very O O
much O O
for O O
coming O O
to O O
my O O
little O O
party O O
. O O
Obstinate O O
silence O O
. O O
They O O
all O O
feared O O
that O O
a O O
song O O
or O O
some O O
poetry O O
was O O
now O O
imminent O O
; O O
and O O
they O O
were O O
getting O O
bored O O
. O O
Why O O
could O O
n't O O
he O O
stop O O
talking O O
and O O
let O O
them O O
drink O O
his O O
health O O
? O O
But O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
did O O
not O O
sing O O
or O O
recite O O
. O O
Fie I-PERSON O
paused O O
for O O
a O O
moment O O
. O O
Thirdly O O
and O O
finally O O
, O O
he O O
said O O
, O O
I O O
wish O O
to O O
make O O
an O O
ANNOUNCEMENT O O
. O O
Fie I-PERSON O
spoke O O
this O O
last O O
word O O
so O O
loudly O O
and O O
suddenly O O
that O O
everyone O O
sat O O
up O O
who O O
still O O
could O O
. O O
I O O
regret O O
to O O
announce O O
that O O
- O O
though O O
, O O
as O O
I O O
said O O
, O O
eleventy-one O O
years O O
is O O
far O O
too O O
short O O
a O O
time O O
to O O
spend O O
among O O
you O O
- O O
this O O
is O O
the O O
END O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
going O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
leaving O O
NOW O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
GOOD-BYE O O
7 O O
He O O
stepped O O
down O O
and O O
vanished O O
. O O
When O O
they O O
opened O O
their O O
eyes O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
nowhere O O
to O O
be O O
seen O O
. O O
One O O
hundred O O
and O O
forty-four O O
flabbergasted O O
hobbits O O
sat O O
back O O
speechless O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
generally O O
agreed O O
that O O
the O O
joke O O
was O O
in O O
very O O
bad O O
taste O O
, O O
and O O
more O O
food O O
and O O
drink O O
were O O
needed O O
to O O
cure O O
the O O
guests O O
of O O
shock O O
and O O
annoyance O O
. O O
` O O
He O O
's O O
mad O O
. O O
I O O
always O O
said O O
so O O
, O O
' O O
was O O
probably O O
the O O
most O O
popular O O
comment O O
. O O
Even O O
the O O
Tooks O O
-LRB- O O
with O O
a O O
few O O
exceptions O O
-RRB- O O
thought O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
's O O
behaviour O O
was O O
absurd O O
. O O
For O O
the O O
moment O O
most O O
of O O
them O O
took O O
it O O
for O O
granted O O
that O O
his O O
disappearance O O
was O O
nothing O O
more O O
than O O
a O O
ridiculous O O
prank O O
. O O
I O O
believe O O
that O O
mad O O
Baggins O O
is O O
off O O
again O O
. O O
Silly O O
old O O
fool O O
. O O
But O O
why O O
worry O O
? O O
He O O
has O O
n't O O
taken O O
the O O
vittles O O
with O O
him O O
. O O
' O O
He O O
called O O
loudly O O
to O O
Frodo O I-PERSON
to O O
send O O
the O O
wine O O
round O O
again O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
the O O
only O O
one O O
present O O
who O O
had O O
said O O
nothing O O
. O O
For O O
some O O
time O O
he O O
had O O
sat O O
silent O O
beside O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-LOCATION
's O O
empty O O
chair O O
, O O
and O O
ignored O O
all O O
remarks O O
and O O
questions O O
. O O
He O O
had O O
enjoyed O O
the O O
joke O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
even O O
though O O
he O O
had O O
been O O
in O O
the O O
know O O
. O O
But O O
at O O
the O O
same O O
time O O
he O O
felt O O
deeply O O
troubled O O
: O O
he O O
realized O O
suddenly O O
that O O
he O O
loved O O
the O O
old O O
hobbit O O
dearly O O
. O O
Most O O
of O O
the O O
guests O O
went O O
on O O
eating O O
and O O
drinking O O
and O O
discussing O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
Baggins I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
' O I-ORGANIZATION
oddities O O
, O O
past O O
and O O
present O O
; O O
but O O
the O O
Sackville-Bagginses I-PERSON I-LOCATION
had O O
already O O
departed O O
in O O
wrath O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
did O O
not O O
want O O
to O O
have O O
any O O
more O O
to O O
do O O
with O O
the O O
party O O
. O O
He O O
gave O O
orders O O
for O O
more O O
wine O O
to O O
be O O
served O O
; O O
then O O
he O O
got O O
up O O
and O O
drained O O
his O O
own O O
glass O O
silently O O
to O O
the O O
health O O
of O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
slipped O O
out O O
of O O
the O O
pavilion O O
. O O
He O O
walked O O
briskly O O
back O O
to O O
his O O
hole O O
, O O
and O O
stood O O
for O O
a O O
moment O O
listening O O
with O O
a O O
smile O O
to O O
the O O
din O O
in O O
the O O
pavilion O O
and O O
to O O
the O O
sounds O O
of O O
merrymaking O O
in O O
other O O
parts O O
of O O
the O O
field O O
. O O
Then O O
he O O
went O O
in O O
. O O
He O O
took O O
off O O
his O O
party O O
clothes O O
, O O
folded O O
up O O
and O O
wrapped O O
in O O
tissue-paper O O
his O O
embroidered O O
silk O O
waistcoat O O
, O O
and O O
put O O
it O O
away O O
. O O
Then O O
he O O
put O O
on O O
quickly O O
some O O
old O O
untidy O O
garments O O
, O O
and O O
fastened O O
round O O
his O O
waist O O
a O O
worn O O
leather O O
belt O O
. O O
From O O
a O O
locked O O
drawer O O
, O O
smelling O O
of O O
moth-balls O O
, O O
he O O
took O O
out O O
an O O
old O O
cloak O O
and O O
hood O O
. O O
They O O
had O O
been O O
locked O O
up O O
as O O
if O O
they O O
were O O
very O O
precious O O
, O O
but O O
they O O
were O O
so O O
patched O O
and O O
weatherstained O O
that O O
their O O
original O O
colour O O
could O O
hardly O O
be O O
guessed O O
: O O
it O O
might O O
have O O
been O O
dark O O
green O O
. O O
They O O
were O O
rather O O
too O O
large O O
for O O
him O O
. O O
He O O
then O O
went O O
into O O
his O O
study O O
, O O
and O O
from O O
a O O
large O O
strong-box O O
took O O
out O O
a O O
bundle O O
wrapped O O
in O O
old O O
cloths O O
, O O
and O O
a O O
leather-bound O O
manuscript O O
; O O
and O O
also O O
a O O
large O O
bulky O O
envelope O O
. O O
The O O
book O O
and O O
bundle O O
he O O
stuffed O O
into O O
the O O
top O O
of O O
a O O
heavy O O
bag O O
that O O
was O O
standing O O
there O O
, O O
already O O
nearly O O
full O O
. O O
Into O O
the O O
envelope O O
he O O
slipped O O
his O O
golden O O
ring O O
, O O
and O O
its O O
fine O O
chain O O
, O O
and O O
then O O
sealed O O
it O O
, O O
and O O
addressed O O
it O O
to O O
Frodo O I-PERSON
. O O
At O O
first O O
he O O
put O O
it O O
on O O
the O O
mantelpiece O O
, O O
but O O
suddenly O O
he O O
removed O O
it O O
and O O
stuck O O
it O O
in O O
his O O
pocket O O
. O O
At O O
that O O
moment O O
the O O
door O O
opened O O
and O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
came O O
quickly O O
in O O
. O O
` O O
Hullo O O
! O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
' O O
I O O
wondered O O
if O O
you O O
would O O
turn O O
up O O
. O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
am O O
glad O O
to O O
find O O
you O O
visible O O
, O O
' O O
replied O O
the O O
wizard O O
, O O
sitting O O
down O O
in O O
a O O
chair O O
, O O
' O O
I O O
wanted O O
to O O
catch O O
you O O
and O O
have O O
a O O
few O O
final O O
words O O
. O O
I O O
suppose O O
you O O
feel O O
that O O
everything O O
has O O
gone O O
off O O
splendidly O O
and O O
according O O
to O O
plan O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
I O O
do O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
Though O O
that O O
flash O O
was O O
surprising O O
: O O
it O O
quite O O
startled O O
me O O
, O O
let O O
alone O O
the O O
others O O
. O O
A O O
little O O
addition O O
of O O
your O O
own O O
, O O
I O O
suppose O O
? O O
' O O
It O O
was O O
. O O
You O O
have O O
wisely O O
kept O O
that O O
ring O O
secret O O
all O O
these O O
years O O
, O O
and O O
it O O
seemed O O
to O O
me O O
necessary O O
to O O
give O O
your O O
guests O O
something O O
else O O
that O O
would O O
seem O O
to O O
explain O O
your O O
sudden O O
vanishment O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
And O O
would O O
spoil O O
my O O
joke O O
. O O
You O O
are O O
an O O
interfering O O
old O O
busybody O O
, O O
' O O
laughed O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
` O O
but O O
I O O
expect O O
you O O
know O O
best O O
, O O
as O O
usual O O
. O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
do O O
- O O
when O O
I O O
know O O
anything O O
. O O
But O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
feel O O
too O O
sure O O
about O O
this O O
whole O O
affair O O
. O O
It O O
has O O
now O O
come O O
to O O
the O O
final O O
point O O
. O O
You O O
have O O
had O O
your O O
joke O O
, O O
and O O
alarmed O O
or O O
offended O O
most O O
of O O
your O O
relations O O
, O O
and O O
given O O
the O O
whole O O
Shire O I-ORGANIZATION
something O O
to O O
talk O O
about O O
for O O
nine O O
days O O
, O O
or O O
ninety-nine O O
more O O
likely O O
. O O
Are O O
you O O
going O O
any O O
further O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
I O O
am O O
. O O
I O O
feel O O
I O O
need O O
a O O
holiday O O
, O O
a O O
very O O
long O O
holiday O O
, O O
as O O
I O O
have O O
told O O
you O O
before O O
. O O
Probably O O
a O O
permanent O O
holiday O O
: O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
expect O O
I O O
shall O O
return O O
. O O
In O O
fact O O
, O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
mean O O
to O O
, O O
and O O
I O O
have O O
made O O
all O O
arrangements O O
. O O
' O O
I O O
am O O
old O O
, O O
Gandalf O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
look O O
it O O
, O O
but O O
I O O
am O O
beginning O O
to O O
feel O O
it O O
in O O
my O O
heart O O
of O O
hearts O O
. O O
Well-preserved O O
indeed O O
! O O
` O O
he O O
snorted O O
. O O
` O O
Why O O
, O O
I O O
feel O O
all O O
thin O O
, O O
sort O O
of O O
stretched O O
, O O
if O O
you O O
know O O
what O O
I O O
mean O O
: O O
like O O
butter O O
that O O
has O O
been O O
scraped O O
over O O
too O O
much O O
bread O O
. O O
That O O
ca O O
n't O O
be O O
right O O
. O O
I O O
need O O
a O O
change O O
, O O
or O O
something O O
. O O
' O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
looked O O
curiously O O
and O O
closely O O
at O O
him O O
. O O
` O O
No O O
, O O
it O O
does O O
not O O
seem O O
right O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
thoughtfully O O
. O O
` O O
No O O
, O O
after O O
all O O
I O O
believe O O
your O O
plan O O
is O O
probably O O
the O O
best O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
I O O
've O O
made O O
up O O
my O O
mind O O
, O O
anyway O O
. O O
In O O
peace O O
and O O
quiet O O
, O O
without O O
a O O
lot O O
of O O
relatives O O
prying O O
around O O
, O O
and O O
a O O
string O O
of O O
confounded O O
visitors O O
hanging O O
on O O
the O O
bell O O
. O O
I O O
might O O
find O O
somewhere O O
where O O
I O O
can O O
finish O O
my O O
book O O
. O O
I O O
have O O
thought O O
of O O
a O O
nice O O
ending O O
for O O
it O O
: O O
and O O
he O O
lived O O
happily O O
ever O O
after O O
to O O
the O O
end O O
of O O
his O O
days O O
. O O
' O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
laughed O O
. O O
I O O
hope O O
he O O
will O O
. O O
But O O
nobody O O
will O O
read O O
the O O
book O O
, O O
however O O
it O O
ends O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Oh O O
, O O
they O O
may O O
, O O
in O O
years O O
to O O
come O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
has O O
read O O
some O O
already O O
, O O
as O O
far O O
as O O
it O O
has O O
gone O O
. O O
You O O
'll O O
keep O O
an O O
eye O O
on O O
Frodo O I-PERSON
, O O
wo O O
n't O O
you O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
I O O
will O O
- O O
two O O
eyes O O
, O O
as O O
often O O
as O O
I O O
can O O
spare O O
them O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
He O O
would O O
come O O
with O O
me O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
if O O
I O O
asked O O
him O O
. O O
In O O
fact O O
he O O
offered O O
to O O
once O O
, O O
just O O
before O O
the O O
party O O
. O O
But O O
he O O
does O O
not O O
really O O
want O O
to O O
, O O
yet O O
. O O
He O O
ought O O
to O O
be O O
comfortable O O
here O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
leaving O O
everything O O
to O O
him O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
except O O
a O O
few O O
oddments O O
. O O
It O O
's O O
time O O
he O O
was O O
his O O
own O O
master O O
now O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Everything O O
? O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
The O O
ring O O
as O O
well O O
? O O
You O O
agreed O O
to O O
that O O
, O O
you O O
remember O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
er O O
, O O
yes O O
, O O
I O O
suppose O O
so O O
, O O
' O O
stammered O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
Where O O
is O O
it O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
In O O
an O O
envelope O O
, O O
if O O
you O O
must O O
know O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
impatiently O O
. O O
` O O
There O O
on O O
the O O
mantelpiece O O
. O O
Well O O
, O O
no O O
! O O
Here O O
it O O
is O O
in O O
my O O
pocket O O
! O O
' O O
He O O
hesitated O O
. O O
` O O
Is O O
n't O O
that O O
odd O O
now O O
? O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
softly O O
to O O
himself O O
. O O
` O O
Yet O O
after O O
all O O
, O O
why O O
not O O
? O O
Why O O
should O O
n't O O
it O O
stay O O
there O O
? O O
' O O
I O O
think O O
, O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
quietly O O
, O O
' O O
I O O
should O O
leave O O
it O O
behind O O
. O O
Do O O
n't O O
you O O
want O O
to O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
Well O O
yes O O
- O O
and O O
no O O
. O O
Now O O
it O O
comes O O
to O O
it O O
, O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
like O O
parting O O
with O O
it O O
at O O
all O O
, O O
I O O
may O O
say O O
. O O
And O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
really O O
see O O
why O O
I O O
should O O
. O O
Why O O
do O O
you O O
want O O
me O O
to O O
? O O
It O O
was O O
sharp O O
with O O
suspicion O O
and O O
annoyance O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
are O O
always O O
badgering O O
me O O
about O O
my O O
ring O O
; O O
but O O
you O O
have O O
never O O
bothered O O
me O O
about O O
the O O
other O O
things O O
that O O
I O O
got O O
on O O
my O O
journey O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
No O O
, O O
but O O
I O O
had O O
to O O
badger O O
you O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
' O O
I O O
wanted O O
the O O
truth O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
important O O
. O O
Magic O O
rings O O
are O O
- O O
well O O
, O O
magical O O
; O O
and O O
they O O
are O O
rare O O
and O O
curious O O
. O O
I O O
was O O
professionally O O
interested O O
in O O
your O O
ring O O
, O O
you O O
may O O
say O O
; O O
and O O
I O O
still O O
am O O
. O O
I O O
should O O
like O O
to O O
know O O
where O O
it O O
is O O
, O O
if O O
you O O
go O O
wandering O O
again O O
. O O
Also O O
I O O
think O O
you O O
have O O
had O O
it O O
quite O O
long O O
enough O O
. O O
You O O
wo O O
n't O O
need O O
it O O
any O O
more O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
unless O O
I O O
am O O
quite O O
mistaken O O
. O O
His O O
kindly O O
face O O
grew O O
hard O O
. O O
` O O
Why O O
not O O
? O O
' O O
he O O
cried O O
. O O
` O O
And O O
what O O
business O O
is O O
it O O
of O O
yours O O
, O O
anyway O O
, O O
to O O
know O O
what O O
I O O
do O O
with O O
my O O
own O O
things O O
? O O
It O O
is O O
my O O
own O O
. O O
I O O
found O O
it O O
. O O
It O O
came O O
to O O
me O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
yes O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
But O O
there O O
is O O
no O O
need O O
to O O
get O O
angry O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
If O O
I O O
am O O
it O O
is O O
your O O
fault O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo O I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
It O O
is O O
mine O O
, O O
I O O
tell O O
you O O
. O O
My O O
own O O
. O O
My O O
precious O O
. O O
Yes O O
, O O
my O O
precious O O
. O O
' O O
The O O
wizard O O
's O O
face O O
remained O O
grave O O
and O O
attentive O O
, O O
and O O
only O O
a O O
flicker O O
in O O
his O O
deep O O
eyes O O
showed O O
that O O
he O O
was O O
startled O O
and O O
indeed O O
alarmed O O
. O O
` O O
It O O
has O O
been O O
called O O
that O O
before O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
, O O
` O O
but O O
not O O
by O O
you O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
But O O
I O O
say O O
it O O
now O O
. O O
And O O
why O O
not O O
? O O
Even O O
if O O
Gollum I-PERSON I-PERSON
said O O
the O O
same O O
once O O
. O O
It O O
's O O
not O O
his O O
now O O
, O O
but O O
mine O O
. O O
And O O
I O O
shall O O
keep O O
it O O
, O O
I O O
say O O
. O O
' O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
stood O O
up O O
. O O
He O O
spoke O O
sternly O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
will O O
be O O
a O O
fool O O
if O O
you O O
do O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
make O O
that O O
clearer O O
with O O
every O O
word O O
you O O
say O O
. O O
It O O
has O O
got O O
far O O
too O O
much O O
hold O O
on O O
you O O
. O O
Let O O
it O O
go O O
! O O
And O O
then O O
you O O
can O O
go O O
yourself O O
, O O
and O O
be O O
free O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
I O O
'll O O
do O O
as O O
I O O
choose O O
and O O
go O O
as O O
I O O
please O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
obstinately O O
. O O
` O O
Now O O
, O O
now O O
, O O
my O O
dear O O
hobbit O O
! O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
All O O
your O O
long O O
life O O
we O O
have O O
been O O
friends O O
, O O
and O O
you O O
owe O O
me O O
something O O
. O O
' O O
cried O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
But O O
you O O
wo O O
n't O O
get O O
it O O
. O O
I O O
wo O O
n't O O
give O O
my O O
precious O O
away O O
, O O
I O O
tell O O
you O O
. O O
' O O
His O O
hand O O
strayed O O
to O O
the O O
hilt O O
of O O
his O O
small O O
sword O O
. O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
s O O
eyes O O
flashed O O
. O O
It O O
will O O
be O O
my O O
turn O O
to O O
get O O
angry O O
soon O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
If O O
you O O
say O O
that O O
again O O
, O O
I O O
shall O O
. O O
' O O
He O O
took O O
a O O
step O O
towards O O
the O O
hobbit O O
, O O
and O O
he O O
seemed O O
to O O
grow O O
tall O O
and O O
menacing O O
; O O
his O O
shadow O O
filled O O
the O O
little O O
room O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
backed O O
away O O
to O O
the O O
wall O O
, O O
breathing O O
hard O O
, O O
his O O
hand O O
clutching O O
at O O
his O O
pocket O O
. O O
They O O
stood O O
for O O
a O O
while O O
facing O O
one O O
another O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
air O O
of O O
the O O
room O O
tingled O O
. O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
s O O
eyes O O
remained O O
bent O O
on O O
the O O
hobbit O O
. O O
Slowly O O
his O O
hands O O
relaxed O O
, O O
and O O
he O O
began O O
to O O
tremble O O
. O O
' O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
know O O
what O O
has O O
come O O
over O O
you O O
, O O
Gandalf O I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
` O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
have O O
never O O
been O O
like O O
this O O
before O O
. O O
What O O
is O O
it O O
all O O
about O O
? O O
It O O
is O O
mine O O
is O O
n't O O
it O O
? O O
I O O
found O O
it O O
, O O
and O O
Gollum O O
would O O
have O O
killed O O
me O O
, O O
if O O
I O O
had O O
n't O O
kept O O
it O O
. O O
I O O
'm O O
not O O
a O O
thief O O
, O O
whatever O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
have O O
never O O
called O O
you O O
one O O
, O O
' O O
Gandalf O I-ORGANIZATION
answered O O
. O O
` O O
And O O
I O O
am O O
not O O
one O O
either O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
not O O
trying O O
to O O
rob O O
you O O
, O O
but O O
to O O
help O O
you O O
. O O
I O O
wish O O
you O O
would O O
trust O O
me O O
, O O
as O O
you O O
used O O
. O O
' O O
He O O
turned O O
away O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
shadow O O
passed O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
drew O O
his O O
hand O O
over O O
his O O
eyes O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
sorry O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
But O O
I O O
felt O O
so O O
queer O O
. O O
And O O
yet O O
it O O
would O O
be O O
a O O
relief O O
in O O
a O O
way O O
not O O
to O O
be O O
bothered O O
with O O
it O O
any O O
more O O
. O O
It O O
has O O
been O O
so O O
growing O O
on O O
my O O
mind O O
lately O O
. O O
Sometimes O O
I O O
have O O
felt O O
it O O
was O O
like O O
an O O
eye O O
looking O O
at O O
me O O
. O O
And O O
I O O
am O O
always O O
wanting O O
to O O
put O O
it O O
on O O
and O O
disappear O O
, O O
do O O
n't O O
you O O
know O O
; O O
or O O
wondering O O
if O O
it O O
is O O
safe O O
, O O
and O O
pulling O O
it O O
out O O
to O O
make O O
sure O O
. O O
I O O
tried O O
locking O O
it O O
up O O
, O O
but O O
I O O
found O O
I O O
could O O
n't O O
rest O O
without O O
it O O
in O O
my O O
pocket O O
. O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
know O O
why O O
. O O
And O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
seem O O
able O O
to O O
make O O
up O O
my O O
mind O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Then O O
trust O O
mine O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
It O O
is O O
quite O O
made O O
up O O
. O O
Go O O
away O O
and O O
leave O O
it O O
behind O O
. O O
Stop O O
possessing O O
it O O
. O O
Give O O
it O O
to O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
and O O
I O O
will O O
look O O
after O O
him O O
. O O
' O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
stood O O
for O O
a O O
moment O O
tense O O
and O O
undecided O O
. O O
Presently O O
he O O
sighed O O
. O O
` O O
All O O
right O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
with O O
an O O
effort O O
. O O
I O O
will O O
. O O
' O O
Then O O
he O O
shrugged O O
his O O
shoulders O O
, O O
and O O
smiled O O
rather O O
ruefully O O
. O O
` O O
After O O
all O O
that O O
's O O
what O O
this O O
party O O
business O O
was O O
all O O
about O O
, O O
really O O
: O O
to O O
give O O
away O O
lots O O
of O O
birthday O O
presents O O
, O O
and O O
somehow O O
make O O
it O O
easier O O
to O O
give O O
it O O
away O O
at O O
the O O
same O O
time O O
. O O
It O O
has O O
n't O O
made O O
it O O
any O O
easier O O
in O O
the O O
end O O
, O O
but O O
it O O
would O O
be O O
a O O
pity O O
to O O
waste O O
all O O
my O O
preparations O O
. O O
It O O
would O O
quite O O
spoil O O
the O O
joke O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Indeed O O
it O O
would O O
take O O
away O O
the O O
only O O
point O O
I O O
ever O O
saw O O
in O O
the O O
affair O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
Very O O
well O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
` O O
it O O
goes O O
to O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
with O O
all O O
the O O
rest O O
. O O
' O O
He O O
drew O O
a O O
deep O O
breath O O
. O O
` O O
And O O
now O O
I O O
really O O
must O O
be O O
starting O O
, O O
or O O
somebody O O
else O O
will O O
catch O O
me O O
. O O
I O O
have O O
said O O
good-bye O O
, O O
and O O
I O O
could O O
n't O O
bear O O
to O O
do O O
it O O
all O O
over O O
again O O
. O O
' O O
He O O
picked O O
up O O
his O O
bag O O
and O O
moved O O
to O O
the O O
door O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
have O O
still O O
got O O
the O O
ring O O
in O O
your O O
pocket O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
the O O
wizard O O
. O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
so O O
I O O
have O O
! O O
' O O
cried O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
You O O
had O O
better O O
take O O
it O O
and O O
deliver O O
it O O
for O O
me O O
. O O
That O O
will O O
be O O
safest O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
No O O
, O O
do O O
n't O O
give O O
the O O
ring O O
to O O
me O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
Put O O
it O O
on O O
the O O
mantelpiece O O
. O O
It O O
will O O
be O O
safe O O
enough O O
there O O
, O O
till O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
comes O O
. O O
I O O
shall O O
wait O O
for O O
him O O
. O O
' O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
took O O
out O O
the O O
envelope O O
, O O
but O O
just O O
as O O
he O O
was O O
about O O
to O O
set O O
it O O
by O O
the O O
clock O O
, O O
his O O
hand O O
jerked O O
back O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
packet O O
fell O O
on O O
the O O
floor O O
. O O
Before O O
he O O
could O O
pick O O
it O O
up O O
, O O
the O O
wizard O O
stooped O O
and O O
seized O O
it O O
and O O
set O O
it O O
in O O
its O O
place O O
. O O
A O O
spasm O O
of O O
anger O O
passed O O
swiftly O O
over O O
the O O
hobbit O O
's O O
face O O
again O O
. O O
Suddenly O O
it O O
gave O O
way O O
to O O
a O O
look O O
of O O
relief O O
and O O
a O O
laugh O O
. O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
that O O
's O O
that O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
Now O O
I O O
'm O O
off O O
! O O
' O O
They O O
went O O
out O O
into O O
the O O
hall O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
chose O O
his O O
favourite O O
stick O O
from O O
the O O
stand O O
; O O
then O O
he O O
whistled O O
. O O
Three O O
dwarves O O
came O O
out O O
of O O
different O O
rooms O O
where O O
they O O
had O O
been O O
busy O O
. O O
` O O
Is O O
everything O O
ready O O
? O O
' O O
asked O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
Everything O O
packed O O
and O O
labelled O O
? O O
' O O
` O O
Everything O O
, O O
' O O
they O O
answered O O
. O O
` O O
Well O O
, O O
let O O
's O O
start O O
then O O
! O O
' O O
He O O
stepped O O
out O O
of O O
the O O
front-door O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
a O O
fine O O
night O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
black O O
sky O O
was O O
dotted O O
with O O
stars O O
. O O
He O O
looked O O
up O O
, O O
sniffing O O
the O O
air O O
. O O
` O O
What O O
fun O O
! O O
What O O
fun O O
to O O
be O O
off O O
again O O
, O O
off O O
on O O
the O O
Road O O
with O O
dwarves O O
! O O
This O O
is O O
what O O
I O O
have O O
really O O
been O O
longing O O
for O O
, O O
for O O
years O O
! O O
Good-bye O O
! O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
, O O
looking O O
at O O
his O O
old O O
home O O
and O O
bowing O O
to O O
the O O
door O O
. O O
` O O
Good-bye O O
, O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
! O O
' O O
` O O
Good-bye O O
, O O
for O O
the O O
present O O
, O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
Take O O
care O O
of O O
yourself O O
! O O
You O O
are O O
old O O
enough O O
, O O
and O O
perhaps O O
wise O O
enough O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Take O O
care O O
! O O
I O O
do O O
n't O O
care O O
. O O
Do O O
n't O O
you O O
worry O O
about O O
me O O
! O O
I O O
am O O
as O O
happy O O
now O O
as O O
I O O
have O O
ever O O
been O O
, O O
and O O
that O O
is O O
saying O O
a O O
great O O
deal O O
. O O
But O O
the O O
time O O
has O O
come O O
. O O
I O O
am O O
being O O
swept O O
off O O
my O O
feet O O
at O O
last O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
added O O
, O O
and O O
then O O
in O O
a O O
low O O
voice O O
, O O
as O O
if O O
to O O
himself O O
, O O
he O O
sang O O
softly O O
in O O
the O O
dark O O
: O O
The O O
Road O O
goes O O
ever O O
on O O
and O O
on O O
Down O O
from O O
the O O
door O O
where O O
it O O
began O O
. O O
Now O O
far O O
ahead O O
the O O
Road O O
has O O
gone O O
, O O
And O O
I O O
must O O
follow O O
, O O
if O O
I O O
can O O
, O O
Pursuing O O
it O O
with O O
eager O O
feet O O
, O O
Until O O
it O O
joins O O
some O O
larger O O
way O O
Where O O
many O O
paths O O
and O O
errands O O
meet O O
. O O
And O O
whither O O
then O O
? O O
I O O
can O O
not O O
say O O
. O O
He O O
paused O O
, O O
silent O O
for O O
a O O
moment O O
. O O
Then O O
without O O
another O O
word O O
he O O
turned O O
away O O
from O O
the O O
lights O O
and O O
voices O O
in O O
the O O
fields O O
and O O
tents O O
, O O
and O O
followed O O
by O O
his O O
three O O
companions O O
went O O
round O O
into O O
his O O
garden O O
, O O
and O O
trotted O O
down O O
the O O
long O O
sloping O O
path O O
. O O
He O O
jumped O O
over O O
a O O
low O O
place O O
in O O
the O O
hedge O O
at O O
the O O
bottom O O
, O O
and O O
took O O
to O O
the O O
meadows O O
, O O
passing O O
into O O
the O O
night O O
like O O
a O O
rustle O O
of O O
wind O O
in O O
the O O
grass O O
. O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
remained O O
for O O
a O O
while O O
staring O O
after O O
him O O
into O O
the O O
darkness O O
. O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
softly O O
and O O
went O O
back O O
indoors O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
came O O
in O O
soon O O
afterwards O O
, O O
and O O
found O O
him O O
sitting O O
in O O
the O O
dark O O
, O O
deep O O
in O O
thought O O
. O O
` O O
Has O O
he O O
gone O O
? O O
' O O
he O O
asked O O
. O O
` O O
Yes O O
, O O
' O O
answered O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
` O O
he O O
has O O
gone O O
at O O
last O O
. O O
' O O
' O O
I O O
wish O O
-1 O O
mean O O
, O O
I O O
hoped O O
until O O
this O O
evening O O
that O O
it O O
was O O
only O O
a O O
joke O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
But O O
I O O
knew O O
in O O
my O O
heart O O
that O O
he O O
really O O
meant O O
to O O
go O O
. O O
He O O
always O O
used O O
to O O
joke O O
about O O
serious O O
things O O
. O O
I O O
wish O O
I O O
had O O
come O O
back O O
sooner O O
, O O
just O O
to O O
see O O
him O O
off O O
. O O
' O O
I O O
think O O
really O O
he O O
preferred O O
slipping O O
off O O
quietly O O
in O O
the O O
end O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf O I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
` O O
Do O O
n't O O
be O O
too O O
troubled O O
. O O
He O O
'll O O
be O O
all O O
right O O
- O O
now O O
. O O
He O O
left O O
a O O
packet O O
for O O
you O O
. O O
There O O
it O O
is O O
! O O
' O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
took O O
the O O
envelope O O
from O O
the O O
mantelpiece O O
, O O
and O O
glanced O O
at O O
it O O
, O O
but O O
did O O
not O O
open O O
it O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
'll O O
find O O
his O O
will O O
and O O
all O O
the O O
other O O
documents O O
in O O
there O O
, O O
I O O
think O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
the O O
wizard O O
. O O
` O O
You O O
are O O
the O O
master O O
of O O
Bag O I-ORGANIZATION
End O I-ORGANIZATION
now O O
. O O
And O O
also O O
, O O
I O O
fancy O O
, O O
you O O
'll O O
find O O
a O O
golden O O
ring O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
The O O
ring O O
! O O
' O O
exclaimed O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
Has O O
he O O
left O O
me O O
that O O
? O O
I O O
wonder O O
why O O
. O O
Still O O
, O O
it O O
may O O
be O O
useful O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
It O O
may O O
, O O
and O O
it O O
may O O
not O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Gandalf I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
. O O
' O O
I O O
should O O
not O O
make O O
use O O
of O O
it O O
, O O
if O O
I O O
were O O
you O O
. O O
But O O
keep O O
it O O
secret O O
, O O
and O O
keep O O
it O O
safe O O
! O O
Now O O
I O O
am O O
going O O
to O O
bed O O
. O O
' O O
As O O
master O O
of O O
Bag O I-ORGANIZATION
End O I-ORGANIZATION
Frodo I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
felt O O
it O O
his O O
painful O O
duty O O
to O O
say O O
good-bye O O
to O O
the O O
guests O O
. O O
Rumours O O
of O O
strange O O
events O O
had O O
by O O
now O O
spread O O
all O O
over O O
the O O
field O O
, O O
but O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
would O O
only O O
say O O
no O O
doubt O O
everything O O
will O O
be O O
cleared O O
up O O
in O O
the O O
morning O O
. O O
About O O
midnight O O
carriages O O
came O O
for O O
the O O
important O O
folk O O
. O O
One O O
by O O
one O O
they O O
rolled O O
away O O
, O O
filled O O
with O O
full O O
but O O
very O O
unsatisfied O O
hobbits O O
. O O
Gardeners O O
came O O
by O O
arrangement O O
, O O
and O O
removed O O
in O O
wheel-barrows O O
those O O
that O O
had O O
inadvertently O O
remained O O
behind O O
. O O
Night O O
slowly O O
passed O O
. O O
The O O
sun O O
rose O O
. O O
The O O
hobbits O O
rose O O
rather O O
later O O
. O O
Morning O O
went O O
on O O
. O O
People O O
came O O
and O O
began O O
-LRB- O O
by O O
orders O O
-RRB- O O
to O O
clear O O
away O O
the O O
pavilions O O
and O O
the O O
tables O O
and O O
the O O
chairs O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
spoons O O
and O O
knives O O
and O O
bottles O O
and O O
plates O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
lanterns O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
flowering O O
shrubs O O
in O O
boxes O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
crumbs O O
and O O
cracker-paper O O
, O O
the O O
forgotten O O
bags O O
and O O
gloves O O
and O O
handkerchiefs O O
, O O
and O O
the O O
uneaten O O
food O O
-LRB- O O
a O O
very O O
small O O
item O O
-RRB- O O
. O O
Then O O
a O O
number O O
of O O
other O O
people O O
came O O
-LRB- O O
without O O
orders O O
-RRB- O O
: O O
Bagginses O O
, O O
and O O
Boffins O O
, O O
and O O
Bolgers O I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
Tooks O O
, O O
and O O
other O O
guests O O
that O O
lived O O
or O O
were O O
staying O O
near O O
. O O
By O O
mid-day O O
, O O
when O O
even O O
the O O
best-fed O O
were O O
out O O
and O O
about O O
again O O
, O O
there O O
was O O
a O O
large O O
crowd O O
at O O
Bag O O
End O O
, O O
uninvited O O
but O O
not O O
unexpected O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
waiting O O
on O O
the O O
step O O
, O O
smiling O O
, O O
but O O
looking O O
rather O O
tired O O
and O O
worried O O
. O O
He O O
welcomed O O
all O O
the O O
callers O O
, O O
but O O
he O O
had O O
not O O
much O O
more O O
to O O
say O O
than O O
before O O
. O O
His O O
reply O O
to O O
all O O
inquiries O O
was O O
simply O O
this O O
: O O
` O O
Mr. O O
Bilbo O I-PERSON
Baggins O I-PERSON
has O O
gone O O
away O O
; O O
as O O
far O O
as O O
I O O
know O O
, O O
for O O
good O O
. O O
' O O
Some O O
of O O
the O O
visitors O O
he O O
invited O O
to O O
come O O
inside O O
, O O
as O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
had O O
left O O
` O O
messages O O
' O O
for O O
them O O
. O O
Inside O O
in O O
the O O
hall O O
there O O
was O O
piled O O
a O O
large O O
assortment O O
of O O
packages O O
and O O
parcels O O
and O O
small O O
articles O O
of O O
furniture O O
. O O
On O O
every O O
item O O
there O O
was O O
a O O
label O O
tied O O
. O O
There O O
were O O
several O O
labels O O
of O O
this O O
sort O O
: O O
For O O
ADELARD O I-PERSON
TOOK O O
, O O
for O O
his O O
VERY O O
OWN O O
, O O
from O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-LOCATION
, O O
on O O
an O O
umbrella O O
. O O
For O O
MILO O I-PERSON
BURROWS O I-PERSON
, O O
hoping O O
it O O
will O O
be O O
useful O O
, O O
from O O
B.B. O I-LOCATION
, O O
on O O
a O O
gold O O
pen O O
and O O
ink-bottle O O
. O O
Milo I-PERSON I-PERSON
never O O
answered O O
letters O O
. O O
For O O
ANGELICA O I-ORGANIZATION
'S O O
use O O
, O O
from O O
Uncle O I-LOCATION
Bilbo I-PERSON I-LOCATION
, O O
on O O
a O O
round O O
convex O O
mirror O O
. O O
She O O
was O O
a O O
young O O
Baggins O O
, O O
and O O
too O O
obviously O O
considered O O
her O O
face O O
shapely O O
. O O
For O O
the O O
collection O O
of O O
HUGO O O
BRACEGIRDLE O O
, O O
from O O
a O O
contributor O O
, O O
on O O
an O O
-LRB- O O
empty O O
-RRB- O O
book-case O O
. O O
For O O
LOBELIA O I-PERSON
SACKVILLE-BAGGINS O I-PERSON
, O O
as O O
a O O
PRESENT O O
, O O
on O O
a O O
case O O
of O O
silver O O
spoons O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
believed O O
that O O
she O O
had O O
acquired O O
a O O
good O O
many O O
of O O
his O O
spoons O O
, O O
while O O
he O O
was O O
away O O
on O O
his O O
former O O
journey O O
. O O
Fobelia I-PERSON I-PERSON
knew O O
that O O
quite O O
well O O
. O O
This O O
is O O
only O O
a O O
small O O
selection O O
of O O
the O O
assembled O O
presents O O
. O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
's O O
residence O O
had O O
got O O
rather O O
cluttered O O
up O O
with O O
things O O
in O O
the O O
course O O
of O O
his O O
long O O
life O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
a O O
tendency O O
of O O
hobbit-holes O O
to O O
get O O
cluttered O O
up O O
: O O
for O O
which O O
the O O
custom O O
of O O
giving O O
so O O
many O O
birthday-presents O O
was O O
largely O O
responsible O O
. O O
Not O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
that O O
the O O
birthday-presents O O
were O O
always O O
new O O
, O O
there O O
were O O
one O O
or O O
two O O
old O O
mathoms O O
of O O
forgotten O O
uses O O
that O O
had O O
circulated O O
all O O
around O O
the O O
district O O
; O O
but O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
had O O
usually O O
given O O
new O O
presents O O
, O O
and O O
kept O O
those O O
that O O
he O O
received O O
. O O
The O O
old O O
hole O O
was O O
now O O
being O O
cleared O O
a O O
little O O
. O O
Every O O
one O O
of O O
the O O
various O O
parting O O
gifts O O
had O O
labels O O
, O O
written O O
out O O
personally O O
by O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
and O O
several O O
had O O
some O O
point O O
, O O
or O O
some O O
joke O O
. O O
But O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
most O O
of O O
the O O
things O O
were O O
given O O
where O O
they O O
would O O
be O O
wanted O O
and O O
welcome O O
. O O
The O O
poorer O O
hobbits O O
, O O
and O O
especially O O
those O O
of O O
Bagshot O I-ORGANIZATION
Row O I-ORGANIZATION
, O O
did O O
very O O
well O O
. O O
Old O O
Gaffer O O
Gamgee I-PERSON O
got O O
two O O
sacks O O
of O O
potatoes O O
, O O
a O O
new O O
spade O O
, O O
a O O
woollen O O
waistcoat O O
, O O
and O O
a O O
bottle O O
of O O
ointment O O
for O O
creaking O O
joints O O
. O O
There O O
was O O
, O O
however O O
, O O
no O O
sign O O
nor O O
mention O O
of O O
money O O
or O O
jewellery O O
: O O
not O O
a O O
penny-piece O O
or O O
a O O
glass O O
bead O O
was O O
given O O
away O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
had O O
a O O
very O O
trying O O
time O O
that O O
afternoon O O
. O O
A O O
false O O
rumour O O
that O O
the O O
whole O O
household O O
was O O
being O O
distributed O O
free O O
spread O O
like O O
wildfire O O
; O O
and O O
before O O
long O O
the O O
place O O
was O O
packed O O
with O O
people O O
who O O
had O O
no O O
business O O
there O O
, O O
but O O
could O O
not O O
be O O
kept O O
out O O
. O O
Some O O
people O O
tried O O
to O O
do O O
swaps O O
and O O
deals O O
in O O
the O O
hall O O
; O O
and O O
others O O
tried O O
to O O
make O O
off O O
with O O
minor O O
items O O
not O O
addressed O O
to O O
them O O
, O O
or O O
with O O
anything O O
that O O
seemed O O
unwanted O O
or O O
unwatched O O
. O O
The O O
road O O
to O O
the O O
gate O O
was O O
blocked O O
with O O
barrows O O
and O O
handcarts O O
. O O
In O O
the O O
middle O O
of O O
the O O
commotion O O
the O O
Sackville-Bagginses O I-PERSON
arrived O O
. O O
` O O
He O O
is O O
indisposed O O
, O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
. O O
` O O
He O O
is O O
resting O O
. O O
' O O
` O O
Hiding O O
, O O
you O O
mean O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Fobelia O I-PERSON
. O O
` O O
Anyway O O
we O O
want O O
to O O
see O O
him O O
and O O
we O O
mean O O
to O O
see O O
him O O
. O O
Just O O
go O O
and O O
tell O O
him O O
so O O
! O O
' O O
Merry I-PERSON I-PERSON
left O O
them O O
a O O
long O O
while O O
in O O
the O O
hall O O
, O O
and O O
they O O
had O O
time O O
to O O
discover O O
their O O
parting O O
gift O O
of O O
spoons O O
. O O
It O O
did O O
not O O
improve O O
their O O
tempers O O
. O O
Eventually O O
they O O
were O O
shown O O
into O O
the O O
study O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
sitting O O
at O O
a O O
table O O
with O O
a O O
lot O O
of O O
papers O O
in O O
front O O
of O O
him O O
. O O
He O O
looked O O
indisposed O O
- O O
to O O
see O O
Sackville-Bagginses I-PERSON I-ORGANIZATION
at O O
any O O
rate O O
; O O
and O O
he O O
stood O O
up O O
, O O
fidgeting O O
with O O
something O O
in O O
his O O
pocket O O
. O O
But O O
he O O
spoke O O
quite O O
politely O O
. O O
They O O
began O O
by O O
offering O O
him O O
bad O O
bargain-prices O O
-LRB- O O
as O O
between O O
friends O O
-RRB- O O
for O O
various O O
valuable O O
and O O
unlabelled O O
things O O
. O O
When O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
replied O O
that O O
only O O
the O O
things O O
specially O O
directed O O
by O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
were O O
being O O
given O O
away O O
, O O
they O O
said O O
the O O
whole O O
affair O O
was O O
very O O
fishy O O
. O O
` O O
Only O O
one O O
thing O O
is O O
clear O O
to O O
me O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Otho I-PERSON I-PERSON
, O O
` O O
and O O
that O O
is O O
that O O
you O O
are O O
doing O O
exceedingly O O
well O O
out O O
of O O
it O O
. O O
I O O
insist O O
on O O
seeing O O
the O O
will O O
. O O
' O O
Otho I-PERSON O
would O O
have O O
been O O
Bilbo I-PERSON I-PERSON
's O O
heir O O
, O O
but O O
for O O
the O O
adoption O O
of O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
. O O
He O O
read O O
the O O
will O O
carefully O O
and O O
snorted O O
. O O
It O O
was O O
, O O
unfortunately O O
, O O
very O O
clear O O
and O O
correct O O
-LRB- O O
according O O
to O O
the O O
legal O O
customs O O
of O O
hobbits O O
, O O
which O O
demand O O
among O O
other O O
things O O
seven O O
signatures O O
of O O
witnesses O O
in O O
red O O
ink O O
-RRB- O O
. O O
` O O
Foiled O O
again O O
! O O
' O O
he O O
said O O
to O O
his O O
wife O O
. O O
` O O
And O O
after O O
waiting O O
sixty O O
years O O
. O O
Spoons O O
? O O
Fiddlesticks O O
! O O
' O O
He O O
snapped O O
his O O
fingers O O
under O O
Frodo O I-PERSON
's O O
nose O O
and O O
slumped O O
off O O
. O O
But O O
Lobelia I-PERSON I-PERSON
was O O
not O O
so O O
easily O O
got O O
rid O O
of O O
. O O
A O O
little O O
later O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
came O O
out O O
of O O
the O O
study O O
to O O
see O O
how O O
things O O
were O O
going O O
on O O
and O O
found O O
her O O
still O O
about O O
the O O
place O O
, O O
investigating O O
nooks O O
and O O
comers O O
and O O
tapping O O
the O O
floors O O
. O O
He O O
escorted O O
her O O
firmly O O
off O O
the O O
premises O O
, O O
after O O
he O O
had O O
relieved O O
her O O
of O O
several O O
small O O
-LRB- O O
but O O
rather O O
valuable O O
-RRB- O O
articles O O
that O O
had O O
somehow O O
fallen O O
inside O O
her O O
umbrella O O
. O O
Her O O
face O O
looked O O
as O O
if O O
she O O
was O O
in O O
the O O
throes O O
of O O
thinking O O
out O O
a O O
really O O
crushing O O
parting O O
remark O O
; O O
but O O
all O O
she O O
found O O
to O O
say O O
, O O
turning O O
round O O
on O O
the O O
step O O
, O O
was O O
: O O
` O O
You O O
'll O O
live O O
to O O
regret O O
it O O
, O O
young O O
fellow O O
! O O
Why O O
did O O
n't O O
you O O
go O O
too O O
? O O
You O O
do O O
n't O O
belong O O
here O O
; O O
you O O
're O O
no O O
Baggins O O
- O O
you O O
- O O
you O O
're O O
a O O
Brandybuck O O
! O O
' O O
` O O
Did O O
you O O
hear O O
that O O
, O O
Merry I-PERSON I-PERSON
? O O
That O O
was O O
an O O
insult O O
, O O
if O O
you O O
like O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
as O O
he O O
shut O O
the O O
door O O
on O O
her O O
. O O
` O O
It O O
was O O
a O O
compliment O O
, O O
' O O
said O O
Merry I-PERSON I-LOCATION
Brandybuck I-PERSON I-LOCATION
, O O
` O O
and O O
so O O
, O O
of O O
course O O
, O O
not O O
true O O
. O O
' O O
Then O O
they O O
went O O
round O O
the O O
hole O O
, O O
and O O
evicted O O
three O O
young O O
hobbits O O
-LRB- O O
two O O
Boffins O O
and O O
a O O
Bolger O I-PERSON
-RRB- O O
who O O
were O O
knocking O O
holes O O
in O O
the O O
walls O O
of O O
one O O
of O O
the O O
cellars O O
. O O
Frodo I-PERSON I-PERSON
also O O
had O O
a O O
tussle O O
with O O
young O O
